CURRICULUM VITAE

Information Technology Officer

Name: Gisele MEKUATE-DEFO

Address: Yaounde, Cameroon

Date of Birth: November 8th, 1989

Nationality: Cameroonian

KEY QUALIFICATIONS:

<u>Website development:</u> a significant knowledge in website development with DRUPAL Content Management System (CMS) and its components. Good in web design and user experience.

<u>System administration</u>: proven knowledge in cloud administration server, mainly ubuntu and Windows distribution, with clear implementation of security policy, deployment of applications and software packages. Familiar with virtualisation and containers implementation.

<u>IT support:</u> Good knowledge on IT related issues on PC, laptops in a networked environment and support to leverage incidents on time.

<u>Programming:</u> advanced skills in developing web applications with python and Java. Related technology and tools includes git, vaadin Framework, Twitter Bootstrap, docker.

<u>Digital communication:</u> Experience in engaging people via social media tools and website. Good knowledge in developing and implementing the social media strategy of organisations. Working knowledge of Google apps. Familiar with Latex and SageMath.

EDUCATION:

Master's degree with honours in Computer Science, University of Picardie Jules Vernes, France, 2013

Bachelor's degree with honours in Software engineering and Databases Management, Institute of Technology Siantou, Cameroon, 2011

EMPLOYMENT RECORD (5 YEARS):

From May 2013 to August 2013 : Website Consultant (03 months)

Regional Agency for Agriculture and Food (RAAF), Lomé, Togo. araa-raaf.org

 Planned, Designed and Developed the website of Climate-Smart Agriculture in West Africa under the implementation of the NEPAD Climate Fund for Regional Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS). The developed website is available at <u>climatechange.ecowas-agriculture.org</u>

From Feb 2015 To Feb 2016: IT Young Professional-P1 (01 year)

USAID/West Africa ITC Young Professional in mission at ECOWAS, Abuja, Nigeria, ecowas.int

- designed, developed and maintained the website of the Directorate of agriculture, <u>ecowas-agriculture.org</u> on the Drupal platform with Mysql database;
- managed cloud server on Linux (Ubuntu distribution) by maintaining software packages, securing web servers and application solutions, and providing access account to users when required;
- developed the data visualization application for regional projects under the implementation of the Agricultural Policy of West Africa with Tableau Public;
- developed engagement of stakeholders through website content and social media publication, targeted emailing lists;
- participated in many conferences, forums and workshops in order to promote activities through communication platforms (website, social media, mailing list).
- supported staff on IT related issues like PC recoveries, wireless networks, configuration, software installation and assisting in use.

From Oct 2013 To Oct 2014: Volunteer (01 year)

USAID/West Africa ITC Volunteer in mission at ECOWAS, Abuja, Nigeria, ecowas.int

- Developed and implemented social media strategy of the Directorate
- operationalised and maintained web applications into a remote ubuntu server
- participated in the meetings related to IT strategy
- supported staff on technical issues related to IT

From Jan 2013 To Oct 2013: IT Project Manager (09months)

Cinema Numérique Ambulant (CNA), Yaounde, Cameroun, cna-afrique.org

- coordinated work of two (02) IT developers in the monitoring and evaluation dedicated software of the organization as a team leader working with agile methodology for planning and follow-up;
- was being involved in the development of the M&E dedicated software of the organization by drafting the technical specification, coding in C# and Microsoft Framework with a PostgresSQL database for queuing data and testing the solution;
- trained staff on the dedicated M&E software application with travel missions on the seven (07) African countries where the organization has offices.
- Supported staff in IT related Issues into a networked environment

From Aug 2010 To Dec. 2012: IT Developer (02 years)

World Engineering Consulting SARL, Yaounde, Cameroon, wec-sarl.com

- drafted technical specification of clients' requirements under software development projects;
- was being involved in developing geographic information system of the Ministry of Tourism of Cameroon, The Touristic Map of Cameroon, with PHP technology and framework, map server and PostgreSql databases;
- was being involved in the design and development of the intranet of the Inter-professional council of Coffee and tea in Cameroon in order to follow up activities in terms of annual productions and provisions of all registered producers within the organisation;
- trained clients on how to use software implemented and installed.

LANGUAGES:

English: Excellent working knowledge in speaking, reading and writing

French: Excellent in speaking, reading and writing (mother tongue)

REFERENCES:

- Mr. Alain Sy Traoré, Director of Agriculture and Rural Development at Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) Commission, Phone: +234 08032596402, atraore@ecowas.int
- Mr. Moukam Géovani, IT project Manager at World Engineering Consulting , Phone: +237 674164844, moukamgeovani@yahoo.fr
- Madam Stéphanie Dongmo, Communication Officer at «Cinéma Numérique Ambulant Afrique», Phone:
 +237 675117662, stephiedjuka@yahoo.fr